Hello there! I want to make sure you have a good time and that you don't get stuck
你好！我希望你玩得愉快，不會遇到困難
on anything relating to connecting to our lab environment. Some of the material
有關連接我們實驗室環境的任何事項。有些材料
you're going to be learning is tricky enough, so you'll have enough on your
你將學習的內容已經很棘手，所以你會有足夠的
mind with just that. Let's make sure that logging into our system and navigating
只需這麼記住。讓我們確認登入系統並導航
around is as smooth and painless as possible. You'll be logging into an
過程盡可能順暢且無痛。您將登入一個
actual IBM Z system, and this is separate from whatever learning platform you're
實際的 IBM Z 系統，這與您使用的學習平台是分開的
on. To get you connected will also be giving you access to a virtual Windows
開機。我們也會提供您虛擬 Windows 的存取權限，以便連線。
system, and that has all of the connection software pre-loaded on it,
系統，並且預先載入所有連接軟體，
and you'll use that to connect to the mainframe system. This is the easiest way
您將使用它來連接大型主機系統。這是最簡單的方法
to get you connected without having you to install all sorts of software on your
讓你連線，而無需安裝各種軟體
own machine. When you go to connect to the lab system, you'll eventually see a
自己的機器。當你連接到實驗室系統時，最終會看到一個
loading screen that looks something like this, and then something like this, and
類似這樣的載入畫面，接著是這樣的畫面，然後是這樣的畫面，最後
then something like this, and then eventually you'll get to a screen that
你會進入一個畫面，大致看起來像這樣，上方有綠色框框和課程實驗套件。這
looks something like this with the green box and the course lab kit up here. This
就是你和系統的連接介面，裡面有三個重要的部分我要介紹給你。首先是上方的實驗套件。 這個連結在系統準備好之前
is your connection to that system, and there's three important things on here
是不會出現的。這是一份專門為你準備的文件，裡面有
that I want to show you. First is the lab kit up top here. That link wasn't there
你的連線資訊。你會需要這份資訊，所以建議你
until the system was ready. This is a document made just for you, and it has
將它加入書籤或列印出來，方便日後查找。這個頁面也
your connection information in it. You'll need that information, so maybe
會顯示剩餘時間。這裡顯示的時間不是
bookmark it or print it out so you can find it easily later on. This page also
剩餘在
shows you the amount of time left. Now, this is not the amount of time left in
內的時間
the course. Remember, two separate things. This is the amount of time left on the
課程。記住，這是兩件不同的事。這是剩餘時間的長度
hands-on system, and if you need more time to get your work done on the system,
在實作系統上，如果你需要更多時間完成工作，
go down to support. There's a link in your course lab kit, and then visit the
請前往支援。有一個連結在你的課程實驗包中，然後拜訪
self-service portal to request an extension, and just so you know, the time
自助服務入口網站申請延長，而且你知道嗎，申請的時機
to do that is before you need that extra time, and the sooner the better. Trust me
必須是在你需要額外時間之前，越早申請越好。相信我，
on this, you don't want to wait until the last minute, or they might not be able to
你不想等到最後一刻，否則他們可能無法及時
change it in time, and you might lose all of your work on that system, so pay
更改，並且你可能會失去該系統上的所有工作，請
attention to that date. Alright, you got that. Last thing is your virtual system.
注意那個日期。好了，你了解了。最後是你的虛擬系統
Access. This is that virtual Windows system that I talked about earlier, and
存取權限。這是我之前提到過的虛擬 Windows 系統，
you'll use this to connect to the IBM Z mainframe system. This will normally say
你會用它連接 IBM Z 大型主機系統。它通常會顯示
running, but if you ever come in here after a while and it says busy, then you
系統正在執行，但如果你過一陣子再進來時顯示忙碌，
probably just have to wait a little while for it to come back online. No big
那你可能得稍微等一下，讓它重新上線。沒什麼大不了的。
deal. This is also a good time to point out that sometimes you'll see values on
此時也是好機會說明，螢幕上有時會顯示範例值。
your screen that are just examples. Things like user IDs and high-level
像是使用者 ID 或高階限定詞之類的。
qualifiers. Now eventually you'll be able to spot those right away, no problem,
漸漸地你會馬上辨識那些範例，沒問題，
but when you see something that maybe looks like your user ID but isn't
但當你看到一個看似你的使用者 ID，卻不是真正的使用者 ID，
actually your user ID, you're probably expected to put in your user ID, not the
你應該輸入自己的使用者 ID，而不是螢幕上看到的那個。
one you see on the screen. You wouldn't believe how often someone copies and
你難以想像有多少人會完全複製貼上命令，
pastes a command exactly as it is into the system, and then they get really
然後當出錯時非常沮喪。
frustrated when it doesn't work. So double check the examples, double check
所以請務必再次確認範例，仔細核對。
the instructions, and make sure you're entering what you're supposed to enter.
請依照指示操作，並確保輸入正確的資料。
To get into this system you'll need a username and password, and I can't tell
要進入此系統，您需要使用者名稱和密碼，我無法
it to you and we can't make it log in automatically. The username and password
告訴您，也無法讓系統自動登入。使用者名稱和密碼
are in your course lab kit. Remember that link up at the top of the screen? Now
在您的課程實驗套件中。還記得螢幕上方的連結嗎？現在
there are two usernames and passwords in here. The first one is for getting into
裡面有兩組使用者名稱和密碼。第一組用於登入
that Windows system. It's in the remote access information section. Then below
Windows 系統，在遠端存取資訊區段。接著在
that in lab information you'll find these student TSO user IDs, and it might
實驗資訊區段，您會找到這些學生 TSO 使用者代號，可能
just be one, it might be two, it'll probably just be one, but you'll use
只有一組，也可能有兩組，通常只有一組，但您會使用
those credentials to log into the mainframe system which we'll cover in the
這些憑證登入大型主機系統，這部分我們會在下一支影片說明。
next video. I hope that helps you get off to a great start with the labs in
希望這能幫助您順利開始實驗。
your course. Have fun and learn a lot.
祝您學習愉快，收穫滿滿。